Guide to the Beecher Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, Speeches, and Research Materials, 1839-1945; Series II; 9' 7" (23 boxes)
  The sermons of Henry Ward Beecher are arranged by order of Old and New Testament books from which the text of the sermon is taken. Each listing includes the text and date of the sermon. Where the text is not given, sermons are listed in chronological order. Sermons without texts or dates are arranged alphabetically by title as are sermon fragments.
  - Bates, Katharine Lee
    - Book of poems written for Annie B. Scoville, 1891 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Poems (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Writings and notes, miscellaneous (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Yellow Clover, Dust cover (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Beecher, Eunice White (Bullard)
    - Reminiscences of Henry Ward Beecher. (Box 47, Folder 5-6)
    - Notes on her husband and family. (Box 47, Folder 7-8)
    - "Romance and Reality" - A Tale of the Far West. (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - "Romance and Reality" cont'd. (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous articles (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Beecher, Henry Ward
    - Sermons - Genesis I:1, undated (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Sermons - Genesis III:4, 1847 December 23 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Sermons - Genesis XIX:20, undated (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Sermons - Genesis XXV:29-34, 1873 January 26 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Sermons - Genesis XL:14-23, 1844 September (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Sermons - Exodus XIV:15, undated (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Sermons - Exodus XX:5,6, 1846 January 4 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Sermons - Exodus XX: 7, 1849 September 2 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Sermons - Deuteronomy XIII:19, 1843 March 23 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Sermons - Deuteronomy XXVII:11-13, 1856 Fall (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Sermons - Deuteronomy XXXLLL:25, 1857 May 30 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Sermons - Joshua VII: 8,9, 1846 July (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Sermons - Joshua XXIV:15, 1849 September 2 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Sermons - I Kings XVIII:21, undated (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Sermons - II Kings XX:1, Undated New Year (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Sermons - I Chronicles XXIX:11, 1839 May 4 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Sermons - Job I:16, 1848 September 10 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Sermons - Job XIX: 27, 1855 July 15 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Sermons - Job XXXVII:6, 1884 December 21 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Sermons - Job XLII:5, 6, 1848 May 14 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Sermons - Psalms XVIII:43, 1877 July 22 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Sermons - Psalms XIX:12, undated (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Sermons - Psalms XXXVII:7, 1851 December 20 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Sermons - Psalms XLII:5, 1849 October (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Sermons - Psalms XLVI:1, 1854 June (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Sermons - Psalms LX:4, undated (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Sermons - Psalms LXVIII:31, 1856 December (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Sermons - Psalms LXXII:23-end, 1862 January 5 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Sermons - Psalms LXXXIV: 4, 1844 April 6 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Sermons - Psalms LXXXV:6, 1850 January 24 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Sermons - Psalms LXXXIX:46, 47, 1846 October 18 (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - Sermons - Psalms CV:1, undated (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - Sermons - Psalms CXXXIX:21-22, undated (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - Sermons - Psalms CXXXIX:33, 34, 1847 October 17 (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - Sermons - Psalms CXLVII:1, undated (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - Sermons - Proverbs V:14, 1848 May 28 (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - Sermons - Proverbs IX:12, 1847 December 1 (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - Sermons - Proverbs XIV:12, 1851 April (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - Sermons - Proverbs XXII:1, 1849 September 23 (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - Sermons - Proverbs XXXIX:1, undated (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - Sermons - Ecclesiastes IX:10, undated (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - Sermons - Ecclesiastes XII:1, undated (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - Sermons - Isaiah I:2, 3, 1839 April (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - Sermons - Isaiah X:3, 1846 January 28 (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - Sermons - Isaiah XIII:11, 1846 January 11 (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - Sermons - Isaiah XXII:8, undated (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - Sermons - Isaiah XXVIII:14-20, 1849 October (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - Sermons - Isaiah XLIII:7, 25, 1871 (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - Sermons - Isaiah LIII:11, 1843 March 12 (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - Sermons - Isaiah LIV: 11, 12, 17, undated (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - Sermons - Isaiah LV: 10, 11, 1846 June (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - Sermons - Jeremiah XIV:7-9, 1838 November 8 (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - Sermons - Jeremiah XXIX:11-13, undated (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - Sermons - Jeremiah XXIX:13, undated (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - Sermons - Ezekiel XVIII:20, 24, undated (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - Sermons - Ezekiel XXXVI:21-32, 1845 December 12 (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - Sermons - Ezekiel XXXVI:37, March 2 (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - Sermons - Daniel IX:3-9, undated (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - Sermons - Hosea IV:17, 1846 September (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - Sermons - Hosea XI:7, undated (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - Sermons - Hosea XIII:9, 1851 May 11 (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - Sermons - Malachi I:8, 1846 February 8 (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - Sermons - Malachi I:8, 1848 January 30 (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - Sermons - Mathew IV:17, 1843 October 22 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - Sermons - Mathew IV:17, 1848 April 23 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - Sermons - Mathew V, undated (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - Sermons - Mathew V:13-16, 1849 February 17 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - Sermons - Mathew V:16, 1886 August 25 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - Sermons - Mathew V:20, 46-48, 1843 August 27 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    - Sermons - Mathew V:48, undated (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Sermons - Mathew VI:9-13, 1862 January 26 (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Sermons - Mathew VI:13, 1859 January 23 (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Sermons - Mathew VI:21, 1846 March 1 (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Sermons - Mathew VI:24-34, 1848 April 16 (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Sermons - Mathew VI:26-27, undated (Box 49, Folder 27)
    - Sermons - Mathew VI:28-30, undated (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Sermons - Mathew VI:33, 1850 December (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Sermons - Mathew VI:33, 1852 February 29 (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Sermons - Mathew VI:33, undated (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Sermons - Mathew X:2-4, 1849 December 16 (Box 49, Folder 28)
    - Sermons - Mathew X:22, undated (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - Sermons - Mathew XI:15, 1847 (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - Sermons - Mathew XII:30, 1847 September 13 (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - Sermons - Mathew XIII:1-15, 1849 February 17 (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - Sermons - Mathew XIII:19-20, undated (Box 49, Folder 29)
    - Sermons - Mathew XIII:31, 1848 June 11 (Box 49, Folder 30)
    - Sermons - Mathew XIII:31, 1848 August 26 (Box 49, Folder 30)
    - Sermons - Mathew XIII:31-32, 1848 June 18 (Box 49, Folder 30)
    - Sermons - Mathew XIII:31-33, 1854 September 5 (Box 49, Folder 30)
    - Sermons - Mathew XIII:38, 1846 May 28 (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Sermons - Mathew XVI:24, 1886 July 8 (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Sermons - Mathew XVIII:1, undated (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Sermons - Mathew XVIII:19, undated (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Sermons - Mathew XX:16, 1850 February 10 (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Sermons - Mathew XX: 16, undated (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Sermons - Mathew XX:22-23, 1845 June 22 (Box 49, Folder 31)
    - Sermons - Mathew XXII:29, 1848 December 3 (Box 49, Folder 32)
    - Sermons - Mathew XXII:36-40, 1848 April (Box 49, Folder 32)
    - Sermons - Mathew XXII:37-40, 1846 April (Box 49, Folder 32)
    - Sermons - Mathew XXII:42, 1849 July (Box 49, Folder 32)
    - Sermons - Mathew XXIII:23, undated (Box 49, Folder 33)
    - Sermons - Mathew XXIV, undated (Box 49, Folder 33)
    - Sermons - Mathew XXV:14, undated (Box 49, Folder 33)
    - Sermons - Mathew XXVI:66, 1847 August 22 (Box 49, Folder 33)
    - Sermons - Mathew XXVII:3-4, 1843 December 3 (Box 49, Folder 33)
    - Sermons - Mathew XXVII:24-25, 1849 July (Box 49, Folder 33)
    - Sermons - Mark I:24, 1846 September (Box 49, Folder 34)
    - Sermons - Mark IV:15-20, undated (Box 49, Folder 34)
    - Sermons - Mark V:28, 1887 February 27 (Box 49, Folder 34)
    - Sermons - Mark VIII:34, 1873 October 19 (Box 49, Folder 34)
    - Sermons - Mark X:13, 1845 May 18 (Box 49, Folder 34)
    - Sermons - Luke II:13, 14, 1838 December 25 (Box 49, Folder 35)
    - Sermons - Luke II:14, 1858 October 31 (Box 49, Folder 35)
    - Sermons - Luke III:3, 7-14, undated (Box 49, Folder 35)
    - Sermons - Luke IX:55, 1848 December 10 (Box 49, Folder 35)
    - Sermons - Luke IX:59, 1849 February 4 (Box 49, Folder 35)
    - Sermons - Luke IX:62, 1849 March 11 (Box 49, Folder 36)
    - Sermons - Luke X:25:28, 1853 April 10 (Box 49, Folder 36)
    - Sermons - Luke X:30, 1848 April 16 (Box 49, Folder 36)
    - Sermons - Luke XII:40, undated (Box 49, Folder 36)
    - Sermons - Luke XII:47, 1847 December 19 (Box 49, Folder 36)
    - Sermons - Luke XIII:23, 24, 1839 September 22 (Box 49, Folder 37)
    - Sermons - Luke XIII:24, 1850 March 3 (Box 49, Folder 37)
    - Sermons - Luke XIII:34, undated (Box 49, Folder 37)
    - Sermons - Luke XIV:28-33, 1846 Fall (Box 49, Folder 37)
    - Sermons - Luke XIV:28-30, 1848 December 31 (Box 49, Folder 37)
    - Sermons - Luke XV:7, 10, 1848 December 31 (Box 49, Folder 38)
    - Sermons - Luke XVI:4, 1887 February 27 (Box 49, Folder 38)
    - Sermons - Luke XVI:8, 1844 August (Box 49, Folder 38)
    - Sermons - Luke XVI:31, 1849 January 21 (Box 49, Folder 38)
    - Sermons - Luke XVIII:7, undated (Box 49, Folder 38)
    - Sermons - Luke XVIII:8, 1855 February 4 (Box 49, Folder 39)
    - Sermons - Luke XIX:26, undated (Box 49, Folder 39)
    - Sermons - Luke XIX:44, 1849 January 21 (Box 49, Folder 39)
    - Sermons - Luke XXIII:39-43, undated (Box 49, Folder 39)
    - Sermons - Luke XXIV:5, 1846 March 8 (Box 49, Folder 39)
    - Sermons - St. John I:10-12, undated (Box 50, Folder 40)
    - Sermons - St. John I:11, undated (Box 50, Folder 40)
    - Sermons - St. John I:11-13, undated (Box 50, Folder 40)
    - Sermons - St. John I:12, 13, 1852 June 18 (Box 50, Folder 40)
    - Sermons - St.John III:1-10, undated (Box 50, Folder 41)
    - Sermons - St. John IV:48, 1847 October 10 (Box 50, Folder 41)
    - Sermons - St. John V:6, 1840 March 25 (Box 50, Folder 41)
    - Sermons - St. John VI:35, undated (Box 50, Folder 41)
    - Sermons - St. John VII:24, 1850 February 14 (Box 50, Folder 41)
    - Sermons - St. John VII:37, undated (Box 50, Folder 42)
    - Sermons - St. John XI:45, 6, 1848 January 2 (Box 50, Folder 42)
    - Sermons - St. John XIII:1, undated (Box 50, Folder 42)
    - Sermons - St. John XIII:34, 1846 July (Box 50, Folder 42)
    - Sermons - St. John XIV:27, 1838 December 2 (Box 50, Folder 42)
    - Sermons - St. John XIV:21, 1885 December 6 (Box 50, Folder 42)
    - Sermons - St. John XV:15, 1848 May 7 (Box 50, Folder 43)
    - Sermons - St.John XV:18-20, 1848 July 16 (Box 50, Folder 43)
    - Sermons - St.John XV:22, 1849 February 25 (Box 50, Folder 43)
    - Sermons - St.John XVI:33, 1859 July 3 (Box 50, Folder 43)
    - Sermons - St.John XVIII:36, 1847 November (Box 50, Folder 43)
    - Sermons - Acts I:9-11, undated (Box 50, Folder 44)
    - Sermons - Acts II:37, 41, 46, 1847 March (Box 50, Folder 44)
    - Sermons - Acts IV:19, 1847 March 28 (Box 50, Folder 44)
    - Sermons - Acts XIII:45, 46, February 18 (Box 50, Folder 44)
    - Sermons - Acts XVII:30-31 (Box 50, Folder 44)
    - Sermons - Acts XIX:34, 1877 June 24 (Box 50, Folder 45)
    - Sermons - Acts XX:18-27, undated (Box 50, Folder 45)
    - Sermons - Acts XX:21, 1876 October 8 (Box 50, Folder 45)
    - Sermons - Acts XXIV:16, undated (Box 50, Folder 45)
    - Sermons - Acts XXVI:28, 1842 February 12 (Box 50, Folder 46)
    - Sermons - Acts XXVI:28, 1844 December 1 (Box 50, Folder 46)
    - Sermons - Acts XXVII:36, undated (Box 50, Folder 46)
    - Sermons - Acts XXVIII:26-29, 1843-1844 (Box 50, Folder 46)
    - Sermons - Romans I:14-16, 1864 June 1 (Box 50, Folder 47)
    - Sermons - Romans I:15, 16, 1848 April 30 (Box 50, Folder 47)
    - Sermons - Romans I:28, 1848 December 10 (Box 50, Folder 47)
    - Sermons - Romans I:28, undated (Box 50, Folder 47)
    - Sermons - Romans II:4, 1855 March (Box 50, Folder 48)
    - Sermons - Romans II:4, 5, 1848 February 27 (Box 50, Folder 48)
    - Sermons - Romans II:9-10, 1838 (Box 50, Folder 48)
    - Sermons - Romans III:23, undated (Box 50, Folder 48)
    - Sermons - Romans V:5, 1853 April 23 (Box 50, Folder 48)
    - Sermons - Romans VI:1, 1849 September (Box 50, Folder 49)
    - Sermons - Romans VII:9, 1876 April 9 (Box 50, Folder 49)
    - Sermons - Romans VII:9, 25, 1849 February 25 (Box 50, Folder 49)
    - Sermons - Romans VII:12, 1842 December 25 (Box 50, Folder 49)
    - Sermons - Romans VII:14-16, 1847 November 28 (Box 50, Folder 49)
    - Sermons - Romans VIII:20-22, 1878 January 20 (Box 50, Folder 50)
    - Sermons - Romans VIII:35039, 1886 March 7 (Box 50, Folder 50)
    - Sermons - Romans X:4, undated (Box 50, Folder 50)
    - Sermons - Romans XII:1, undated (Box 50, Folder 50)
    - Sermons - Romans XIV:7, 8, 1875 (Box 50, Folder 51)
    - Sermons - Romans XIV:13-23, undated (Box 50, Folder 51)
    - Sermons - Romans XV:1-4 (Box 50, Folder 51)
    - Sermons - Romans XV:2, 3 (Box 50, Folder 51)
    - Sermons - I Corinthians I:17, 1847 October 10 (Box 50, Folder 52)
    - Sermons - I Cornithians I:18, 1863 November 21 (Box 50, Folder 52)
    - Sermons - I Corinthians I:30, 1843 (Box 50, Folder 52)
    - Sermons - I Cornithians II:4-5, undated (Box 50, Folder 52)
    - Sermons - I Cornithians VII:17, undated (Box 50, Folder 52)
    - Sermons - I Corinthians VIII:4, undated (Box 50, Folder 53)
    - Sermons - I Corinthians VIII:9, 1862 December 28 (Box 50, Folder 53)
    - Sermons - I Corinthians X:28, 29, 1875 March 21 (Box 50, Folder 53)
    - Sermons - I Corinthians X:31, 1846 April 25 (Box 50, Folder 53)
    - Sermons - I Corinthians XIII:8-end, 1876 May 28 (Box 50, Folder 54)
    - Sermons - I Corinthians XIII:9, 10, undated (Box 50, Folder 54)
    - Sermons - I Corinthians XV:25, undated (Box 50, Folder 54)
    - Sermons - I Corinthians XV:58, 1838 June 17 (Box 50, Folder 54)
    - Sermons - II Corinthians I:34, 1868 September 27 (Box 50, Folder 55)
    - Sermons - II Corinthians III:18, 1848 May 14 (Box 50, Folder 55)
    - Sermons - II Corinthians VI:16, undated (Box 50, Folder 55)
    - Sermons - II Corinthians VII:10, undated (Box 50, Folder 55)
    - Sermons - II Corinthians IX:, undated (Box 50, Folder 55)
    - Sermons - II Corinthians XII:4, 5, undated (Box 50, Folder 55)
    - Sermons - Galatians I:4, undated (Box 51, Folder 56)
    - Sermons - Galatians IV:9, 1852 June 6 (Box 51, Folder 56)
    - Sermons - Galatians V:1, undated (Box 51, Folder 56)
    - Sermons - Galatians V:6, 1844 January (Box 51, Folder 56)
    - Sermons - Galatians V:7, 1859 September 18 (Box 51, Folder 56)
    - Sermons - Galatians V:22, undated (Box 51, Folder 56)
    - Sermons - Galatians VI:3, 4, undated (Box 51, Folder 57)
    - Sermons - Galatians VI:7, 1848 November 19 (Box 51, Folder 57)
    - Sermons - Galatians VI:9, 1848 February 20 (Box 51, Folder 57)
    - Sermons - Galatians VI:9, undated (Box 51, Folder 57)
    - Sermons - Galatians VI:9, 10, 1856 November 8 (Box 51, Folder 57)
    - Sermons - Ephesians IV: 13, 14, 1852 April 11 (Box 51, Folder 58)
    - Sermons - Ephesians V:15, 16, 1840 Jan:5 (Box 51, Folder 58)
    - Sermons - Ephesians VI:1, 1848 April 9 (Box 51, Folder 58)
    - Sermons - Ephesians VI:5-8, 1876 June 4 (Box 51, Folder 58)
    - Sermons - Ephesians VI:13, 1873 November 2 (Box 51, Folder 58)
    - Sermons - Philippians I:29, undated (Box 51, Folder 58)
    - Sermons - Philippians II:5-9, 1856 September (Box 51, Folder 59)
    - Sermons - Philippians II:12, 1852 May 25 (Box 51, Folder 59)
    - Sermons - Philippians II:14, undated (Box 51, Folder 59)
    - Sermons - Philippians III:13, 1854 January 2 (Box 51, Folder 59)
    - Sermons - Philippians IV:4, 1858 November 18 (Box 51, Folder 59)
    - Sermons - I Thessalonians IV:11, 12, 1853 (Box 51, Folder 60)
    - Sermons - I Thessalonians V:3, 1839 November 10 (Box 51, Folder 60)
    - Sermons - I Thessalonians V:16, 1849 (Box 51, Folder 60)
    - Sermons - I Timothy I:5, 1858 June (Box 51, Folder 60)
    - Sermons - I Timothy II:1, 1849 September (Box 51, Folder 60)
    - Sermons - I Timothy VI:12 (Box 51, Folder 60)
    - Sermons - II Timothy III:15-17, undated (Box 51, Folder 60)
    - Sermons - Hebrews IV:9, 1854 January 14 (Box 51, Folder 61)
    - Sermons - Hebrews X:19-24, undated (Box 51, Folder 61)
    - Sermons - Hebrews X:28-31, 1847 October (Box 51, Folder 61)
    - Sermons - Hebrews X:35, 36, 1855 June 17 (Box 51, Folder 61)
    - Sermons - Hebrews XI:1, 1856 April 17 (Box 51, Folder 61)
    - Sermons - Hebrews XI:4, undated (Box 51, Folder 62)
    - Sermons - Hebrews XI:27, 1850 April (Box 51, Folder 62)
    - Sermons - Hebrews XI:38, undated (Box 51, Folder 62)
    - Sermons - Hebrews XII, 1847 May 31 (Box 51, Folder 62)
    - Sermons - Hebrews XII:1-3, 1849 July-August (Box 51, Folder 63)
    - Sermons - Hebrews XII:1-3, 1855 May 6 (Box 51, Folder 63)
    - Sermons - Hebrews XII:7, 1853 July 3 (Box 51, Folder 63)
    - Sermons - Hebrews XII:15-17, 1849 September (Box 51, Folder 63)
    - Sermons - Hebrews XII:17, undated (Box 51, Folder 63)
    - Sermons - Hebrews XII:22, undated (Box 51, Folder 63)
    - Sermons - James I:27, 1840 May 10 (Box 51, Folder 64)
    - Sermons - James IV:6, 10, undated (Box 51, Folder 64)
    - Sermons - James IV:7, undated (Box 51, Folder 64)
    - Sermons - I Peter II:21, undated (Box 51, Folder 64)
    - Sermons - I Peter IV:3, 1848 December 24 (Box 51, Folder 64)
    - Sermons - I Peter IV:12, undated (Box 51, Folder 65)
    - Sermons - I Peter V:7, 1852 September 12 (Box 51, Folder 65)
    - Sermons - I Peter V:10, undated (Box 51, Folder 65)
    - Sermons - I John II:2, 1842 August 28 (Box 51, Folder 66)
    - Sermons - Revelation II:17, 1866 July 1 (Box 51, Folder 66)
    - Sermons - Revelation IV:11, 1848 September 24 (Box 51, Folder 66)
    - Sermons - Revelation XIV:2, 3, 5, 1848 September [3] (Box 51, Folder 66)
    - Sermons - Revelation XXII:4, 5, 1876 April 2 (Box 51, Folder 67)
    - Sermons - Revelation XXII:17, 1849 January 7 (Box 51, Folder 67)
    - Sermons - Revelation XXII:17, undated (Box 51, Folder 67)
    - Dated Sermons
      - Thanksgiving, [1839 November 28] (Box 52, Folder 68)
      - Political Duties of Christians, 1842 August (Box 52, Folder 69)
      - "Paul" - Sermon delivered in 1842 and 1848, 1842, 1848 (Box 52, Folder 70)
      - "Divinity of Christ" sermon delivered on various occasions between 1842 and 1849, 1842-1849 (Box 52, Folder 71)
      - Arguments for Christianity, 1843 June (Box 52, Folder 72)
      - The Unconverted Man, 1844 (Box 52, Folder 73)
      - "Except A Man Be Born Again", 1844-1847 (Box 52, Folder 74)
      - On Temperance, [1846?] (Box 52, Folder 75)
      - On Divine Punishment, 1846 January 17 (Box 52, Folder 76)
      - Slavery, 1846, May (Box 52, Folder 77)
      - On Slavery, 1846 October (Box 52, Folder 78)
      - Sermon against the Mexican War, 1848 April 27 (Box 52, Folder 79)
      - On Christianity and Human Rights as applied to the slavery question., [c.1850's] (Box 52, Folder 80)
      - The New Testament and Slavery, [1850's] (Box 52, Folder 81)
      - "Anti-Nebraska", [c.1854-1855] (Box 52, Folder 82)
      - How to Become a Christian (1862), 1858 March (Box 52, Folder 83)
      - "The Harper's Ferry Tragedy" [Extra from the New York Sun ], 1859 October 10 (Box 52, Folder 84)
      - Sermon on the Divine Government of Nations, as displayed in the slavery question, 1862 September (Box 52, Folder 85)
      - Death of Rev. Albert Barnes [fragment], [1870] (Box 52, Folder 86)
      - Boston fire sermon, [1872 November 10?] (Box 52, Folder 86a)
      - On fellowship within the church, 1877 (Box 52, Folder 87)
      - Past Perils and the Peril of Today (1877), 1877 November 29 (Box 52, Folder 88)
      - On the Bible and Personal Experience, 1878 (Box 52, Folder 89)
      - "Early Marriages Permanent Moralities", 1878 (Box 52, Folder 90)
      - "Love & Hate, A Statement of Belief", 1880 July 11 (Box 52, Folder 90A)
      - Assassination of President Garfield [typescript], 1881 July 3 (Box 52, Folder 91)
      - Death of President Garfield - Draft [pp 3-17 missing], [1881 Sep] (Box 52, Folder 92)
      - Death of Garfield [Supplement to the Christian Union ], 1881 September 25 (Box 52, Folder 93)
      - A Circuit of the Continent (N.Y., 1884), 1883 November 29 (Box 52, Folder 94)
      - Wendell Phillips - draft (Box 52, Folder 95)
      - Wendell Phillips: A Commemorative Discourse (1884) [2 copies], 1884 February 10 (Box 52, Folder 96)
      - Thanksgiving Sermon(?), 1884 November 27 (Box 52, Folder 97)
    - Undated Sermons
      - On Abraham, undated (Box 52, Folder 98)
      - On Alcohol, undated (Box 52, Folder 99)
      - On the Atonement, undated (Box 52, Folder 100)
      - Burgess, Daniel, Funeral Sermon, undated (Box 52, Folder 101)
      - Changing Religious Thought, undated (Box 52, Folder 102)
      - On Christian Witness, undated (Box 52, Folder 103)
      - Against "Clerical Manners", undated (Box 52, Folder 104)
      - On Conversion, undated (Box 52, Folder 105)
      - Cornelius and Peter, undated (Box 52, Folder 106)
      - Death and the Future State, undated (Box 52, Folder 107)
      - On the Difficulty of Attaining Religion [incomplete], undated (Box 52, Folder 108)
      - On Divine Government, undated (Box 52, Folder 109)
      - "The Elements of Happiness", undated (Box 52, Folder 110)
      - "The Emancipator", undated (Box 52, Folder 111)
      - On "The Exceeding Lawlessness of Our Nation", undated (Box 52, Folder 112)
      - Christ the Living Redeemer, undated (Box 52, Folder 113)
      - On the Doctrine of Faith and Works, undated (Box 52, Folder 114)
      - The Gates of Prayer, undated (Box 52, Folder 115)
      - Greeley, Horace [fragment], undated (Box 52, Folder 116)
      - Growth in Grace, undated (Box 52, Folder 117)
      - "Historical View of Man's Sinfulness", undated (Box 53, Folder 118)
      - Home Missions, undated (Box 53, Folder 119)
      - How Far May We Cooperate with Bad Men in the Promotion of Good Objects, undated (Box 53, Folder 120)
      - "The Influence of Modern Science On Religious Beliefs", undated (Box 53, Folder 121)
      - Knowledge of God Through Growth in Grace [incomplete], undated (Box 53, Folder 122)
      - On Love and Humanity, undated (Box 53, Folder 123)
      - On Love of the Beautiful, undated (Box 53, Folder 124)
      - On Man's Sinfulness and Danger, undated (Box 53, Folder 125)
      - On the "Measure of Duty", undated (Box 53, Folder 126)
      - Ministerial Labors in the Mississippi Valley, undated (Box 53, Folder 127)
      - The Ministry [copy], undated (Box 53, Folder 128)
      - The Ministry, Fitness For, undated (Box 53, Folder 129)
      - "Nature and Operation of Love", undated (Box 53, Folder 130)
      - October, undated (Box 53, Folder 131)
      - "Paul and His Writings", undated (Box 53, Folder 132)
      - "Paul's Theology", undated (Box 53, Folder 133)
      - "Present Condition of the World", undated (Box 53, Folder 134)
      - "Prophecy[sic] of Destruct[ion] [of] Jerusalem", undated (Box 53, Folder 135)
      - On Public Duties [fragment], undated (Box 53, Folder 136)
      - "Relation of Ideality to Morals", undated (Box 53, Folder 137)
      - Religious Gains of the Past Century, undated (Box 53, Folder 138)
      - The Religious Training of Children, undated (Box 53, Folder 139)
      - On Repentance, undated (Box 53, Folder 140)
      - On Self-Denial [incomplete], undated (Box 53, Folder 141)